Xiangchong(Chris) Liu

(213)-509-3210 | xiangchong95@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/chrisliu95 chrisliu95.com | Los Angeles, CA

SUMMARY

Data Science track master student at USC with experience in big data, cloud computing, front-end development and machine learning. Strong knowledge of Python, JavaScript, html/CSS, familiarity with AWS, Git, Agile Development & Scrum. Currently a full-stack engineer intern at Edmunds, working in ads team. Quick learner, Passionate about exploring new technologies. Interested in software development and related full-time opportunities.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science, Viterbi Engineering School

08/2017 - 05/2019

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA (GPA: 3.56/4.00)

Bachelor of Engineering in Telecommunications with Management, International School Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, China (GPA: 3.70/4.00)

09/2013 - 06/2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Edmunds, Full-Stack Engineer Intern, Edmunds Ads team, Los Angeles, CA

05/2018 - present

This internship aims to develop and optimize ads performance of Edmunds.com to increase the number of users interested in purchasing vehicles. Improved the loading performance of ads on Edmunds core page by 40%, by breaking up ads call and implementing lazy load.

- Designed and implemented new AMP version of ads template, which is 50% faster than previous version on mobile.

Participated in Edmunds Intern program as team leader, completed a ML project which helps making smart recommendation.

Institute of Microelectronics of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Research Assistant, Beijing, China

- Participated in the research on core technology of NDIR gas detection system.
- C Programming for controllable multiples magnification and noise reduction processing of the weak signal output by sensors.
- Built the SPI communications between gas sensor and ARM, and output the concentration of gas.

GWC (Great Wall Club), Data Analyst Intern, Beijing, China

04/2017 - 06/2017

- Analyze customers' information and finalize target customers, update data on both website and database.
- Organized the G-Startup Worldwide competition of Global Mobile Internet Conference (GMIC) in Beijing.

PROJECTS

Car Make Recognition

06/2018 - 08/2018

- Trained an image recognition model which can recognize car make with 90% accuracy based on TensorFlow.
- Designed an API and deployed model to apache server, also built a user-friendly UI.

Travel and Entertainment Search Engine

02/2018 - 03/2018

- Created a webpage and designed an android app which allows user to search for places information by using Google Places API, also provide map, reviews and photos.
- Node.js/PHP server-side scripting, HTML/CSS, JavaScript/AngularJS and Bootstrap included. (Deployed at AWS)

AWS Network Simulation

11/2017

Socket programming by C (Python), Built the TCP/UDP connections between user, AWS server, and back-end server.

Sightseeing Vehicle Management System; Team Leader

03/2016 - 05/2016

- Responsible for project management, requirement and design analysis, implementation and testing.
- Assigned tasks, arranged weekly meetings, tracks of backlog work to be done, programming of Java project.

Intelligent Lamp; *Team Leader*

06/2015 - 10/2015

- Organized weekly team meeting, managed electronic components and wrote Arduino electric board program (C Language).
- Coordinated the welding of electronic components and appearance design, product instructions and advertising video production.

SKILLS

Programming Language

Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Java, C, PHP, MySQL

AWS Cloud Computing

Operating Systems Mac OS, Linux, Windows Others Git, Agile Development & Scrum

PULICATIONS

Anjie Ming, Xiangchong Liu, et al. 2018. Smart Sensor Systems: Emerging Technologies and Applications (Translation Edition). Beijing, China: China Machine Press. 261pp.